生活大爆炸前情回顾...
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
我还在纠结
I guess I'm still wondering
我和Emily相不相配
if Emily and I are right for each other.
这和与你一起喝咖啡的妹子有关系吗?
Does this have to do with that girl you had coffee with?
你是指我满脑子想的那位强大的性感天使?
You mean the strong, sexy angel I can't stop thinking about?
谁知道呢?
Who can say?
我得想出个挣钱的大招
I need to come up with a big idea to make some money.
- 这应该不难  - 你说得容易
- There's no reason you can't.  - That's easy for you to say.
你和Sheldon早就提出了
You and Sheldon already came up
超流氦模型
with your superfluid helium model.
那只是研究
That's just research.
我们从中挣不了钱
We're never going to make any money from it.
管它氦不氦的... 真正的超流体
Forget helium... the real superfluid
是这杯子里的水果酒
is the fruit punch in this mug.
让我想起了老爸秘制的"别告诉妈妈"果汁
It reminds me of my daddy's secret "Don't Tell Mama" juice.
这也许是个好主意
Maybe that's an idea.
醉酒人士的导航系统
Guidance systems for drunk people.
已经有了 叫优步
They have that, it's called Uber.
在你们的过冷氦气实验中
Hey, in your supercooled helium experiments,
你们有制造出量子漩涡吗?
did you create quantum vortices?
有啊 怎么了?
Yeah, why?
如果你制造一个指引系统
Well, if you made a guidance system,
可不可以用这些漩涡作为陀螺仪?
couldn't you use those vortices as a gyroscope?
哇哦 我倒从来没这样想过
Wow. Never thought about that.
而且既然处于量子态
And, since it's in a quantum state,
就可以保持永久的持续性
it would maintain an infinite persistence.
激动人心的剧情发展
Groundbreaking revelations,
还有鸡尾酒
tropical drinks.
这简直是欲望都市中最精彩的一集
Tell me this isn't like the best episode of Sex and the City.
现在...
我得问一句...
Okay, I gotta ask...
你干啥要戴领结啊?
why are you wearing a bow tie?
我还从来没申请过专利呢
I've never applied for a patent before.
我想给他一个好的印象
I wanted to make a good impression.
哦 你是想让他以为你是喜剧演员?
Oh. Is the impression that your first name is Pee-Wee?
你还是工程师呢
Yeah, well, you're an engineer.
笑话说完了
End of joke, burn.
进来吧
Come on in, fellas.
你看 他也没有戴领带啊
See, he's not wearing a tie.
他是专利律师
Well, he's a patent attorney.
说不定他的领带还没批下来呢
Maybe his tie is pending.
我已经看过你们的文件了
So, I've reviewed your paperwork,
看样子你们该有的东西都有了
and it seems like we've got everything we need
可以为你发明的
to file a patent
无限持续性陀螺仪申请专利了
for your infinite persistence gyroscope.
太好了! 真棒
That's great! Excellent.
接下来怎么办?
So what happens next?
我们的法律团队需要检查一下
Well, the legal team needs to review
确保你们的专利和已经存在的专利没有重复
existing patents to avoid overlap.
我觉得应该没有
Oh, I don't think there will be.
是啊 我们自己考证过
Yes, we did our own search.
真好 不过我觉得我们能查得更彻底点
That's nice, but I think ours might be a bit more thorough.
听听他说的
Get a load of this guy.
你能想象我们用这个赚钱吗?
Can you imagine if we make money with this?
如果我们能赚钱的话
If we do, I am splurging
我要买全世界最贵的鼻腔冲洗器
on the best sinus irrigator money can buy.
就像故事里说的那样...
That old sad story...
一个人赚了点小钱 全塞自己鼻孔里了
guy gets a little money, goes straight up his nose.
现在你们只需要看一下这份文件并签字
Just need you to review and sign this document
表示你们同意大学校方
acknowledging that you understand the university
拥有你们专利权的百分之七十五
will own 75% of the patent.
百分之七十五?
75%?
这太扯淡了
That's outrageous.
这是我们自己研究出来的主意
This is our idea based on our research.
学校凭什么占这么大的权重啊?
How can you possibly justify owning a majority share?
这是学校的政策
It's university policy.
好吧我认输
I know when I'm beat.
等等 等等 也就是说所有的事
Hold on, hold on. So the three of us
都是我们三个人干的 而我们只能拿百分之二十五?
do all the work and only end up with 25%?
Hofstadter博士 大学校方
Dr. Hofstadter, this university
十年来一直都在付你的薪水
has been paying your salaries for over ten years.
你以为我们付你钱是因为我们好心吗?
Did you think we do that out of the goodness of our hearts?
你要没说这种话我还真的这么想呢
Well, until you just said that mean thing, kinda.
而且Wolowitz先生的情况也不一样
And as far as Mr. Wolowitz is concerned,
你是公务员而且有国家航空航天局的贷款
I'm afraid as a federal employee on loan from NASA,
专利上可以写你的名字
your name can be on the patent,
但是你不能拿专利的股权
but you're not entitled to an ownership share.
等等 也就是说
Wait, so this can turn out to be
这个可能会赚大钱 但我什么都拿不到?
a financial success, and I get nothing?
有时候他们会给你个名牌
Well, sometimes they give you a plaque.
这不公平啊
Well, that's not fair.
我们应该都拿得到名牌啊
We should all get plaques.
不好意思 我们不能签字
Sorry, but we can't sign this.
我们走吧
Come on, let's go.
谢谢你为我们花时间
Thank you for your time.
我再问几个关于名牌的事...
Couple of questions about the plaque...
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第18集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥要变瘦 影纸要变胖
校对: UUUU要翘臀
翻译: 小黄小可爱 波特妹子 钥匙君 李小宝Licht AU薇
你有晨吐吗?
So, have you been having any morning sickness?
有一点
A little.
我的嗅觉变灵敏了
And it doesn't help
也不是件好事
that I've got this heightened sense of smell.
- 是因为怀孕吗?  - 对
- Is that a pregnancy thing?  - Yeah.
有一天我闻出来
The other day I sniffed out
Howie把女童子军饼干藏哪了
where Howie hid the Girl Scout cookies.
不做跟屁虫 骗鬼呢
No more Tagalongs, my ass.
但现在你可以自己
But now you'll be able to make
挤奶泡饼干吃了
your own milk to eat the cookies with.
大家好 嘿 Penny
Hey, guys. Hey, Penny.
太感谢你能帮忙了
I really appreciate you helping me with this.
我实在不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
- 没事 让我看看  - 看什么?
- Oh, sure. Let me see it.  - See what?
我和Emily分手后就再没跟她说过话了
I hadn't spoken to Emily since I broke up with her,
她把这个带张纸条放我家台阶上了
and she left this on my doorstep with a note.
"Raj 这是我在分手前要给你的 现在退不掉了
"Raj, I got you this before we split up, but couldn't return it
"你应该会喜欢的
"and thought you'd like to have it.
迟到的情人节快乐 Emily"
Happy belated Valentine's Day, Emily"
好贴心
That's nice.
贴心 还是试图玩弄他?
Nice, or is she trying to manipulate him?
我知道 我该打开吗? 还是退回去?
I know. I mean, do I open it? Do I return it?
为什么不打开啊?
Why wouldn't you open it?
她当时特别生气
Well, she was pretty mad.
万一是个我的被插鸡鸡的
For all I know it's a voodoo doll of me
巫毒娃娃呢
with a fork stuck in my junk.
你不会真的认为她会给你寄一些
You don't think she'd actually send you something gross
恶心或危险的东西吧?
or dangerous, do you?
我有个办法找答案... 闻一下
I know one way to find out... sniff this.
她怀孕了 又不是刑侦犬
She's pregnant, she's not a bloodhound.
但我闻到了些许机油的气味
Although I am getting a little machine oil.
我觉得是金属
I think it's metal.
哎呀 打开就是了
Come on, just open it.
你知道吗 在权力的游戏里
You know, on Game of Thrones,
葛雷乔伊儿子的生殖器被装在盒子送给他了
Balon Greyjoy received his son's genitals in a box.
有个备用的也不错
Well, never hurts to have a spare.
这是什么?
What is that?
哇 是古董六分仪
Wow. It's an antique sextant.
水手们用它靠星星来辨别方位
Sailors used these to find their position by the stars.
这礼物太适合天体物理学家了
What a nice gift for an astrophysicist.
对吧 她太有心了
I know, she's so thoughtful.
看到没 她想跟你和好呢
See, she's trying to get you back.
我要是知道这是什么玩意或者你的职业
Now, that is exactly what I would've gotten you
我也会送你一模一样的东西的
if I had any idea what it is or what you do.
跟你们说 我自尊心太强了
You know, I have too much self-esteem to let this girl
绝不能因为内疚跟她和好
guilt me into getting back together with her.
不用怀孕都嗅得出这屁话
You don't need to be pregnant to smell that load of crap.
要是我们不经过学校
Well, what if we go around the university
自己申请专利呢?
and just get the patent ourselves?
不行 他们网站上说了
We can't. It says on their Web site,
只要我们还在这儿工作
as long as we work there, they have
他们就拥有我们所有的智力财产
a controlling ownership of anything we come up with.
得 那我在衬衫上印
Great, so they own my idea for a T-shirt
"蠢比地质学家"的主意也归他们了
that says "Dumb as a Bag of Geologists."
我们的选择就是要么跟学校合作
Well, our choices are we do this with the university
要么根本不申请
or we don't do it at all.
不管哪个 我都捞不着
Either way, I get nothing.
或者 要是我们能从这个上面赚钱
Or, if we ended up making money from this,
Sheldon和我可以跟你分红
Sheldon and I could split our shares with you.
话说清楚
To be clear,
Leonard指的是陀螺仪
Leonard is referring to the gyroscope,
而非短袖和杯子
not the T-shirt and mugs.
哦! 现在杯子也是他们的了
Oh! Now they own the mugs.
这也算是一种解决办法吧
I guess that is a way around this.
这样你们没有意见吗?
You guys would be cool doing it like that?
当然 任何盈利都可以分成三份
Of course, we can split any profits three ways.
我没意见
I'm fine with that.
好 太好了
Okay, great.
看来接下来应该签合同了
It sounds like a, uh, contract might be in order.
嗯 我们可以拟个合同
Sure, we could write something up.
那该选我们当中哪一个来...
But which one of us should be the party who...
交给你了 Sheldon
You can do it, Sheldon.
一言为定!
So stipulated!
我曾经看到他在床底下藏的合同
Once I found a stash of contracts under his bed.
相当怪异
It was weird.
不知道她花了多少钱买这个
I wonder how much she spent on this.
哦 我们查一下
Ooh, let's find out.
钱不要紧
It doesn't matter.
心意才重要
It's the thought that counts.
是啊 是啊 内心美才是真的美
Yeah, yeah, and beauty's on the inside,
尺寸不重要... 她花了多少钱?
size doesn't matter... how much she spend?
说实话 各位 我不想知道
Seriously, guys, I don't want to know.
我天
Oh, my.
哦 别这样 你不能光说"我天" 然后不告诉我多少钱
Oh, come on, you can't say "Oh, my," and then not tell me!
这些东西总共要500多美元
These things go for $500 and up.
我去
Damn.
我的情人节礼物就只是一张卡片
All I got for Valentine's Day was a postcard
告诉我我订的佛蒙特泰迪熊没货了
saying my Vermont Teddy Bear was back-ordered.
好 所以 她留了
Okay, so, she drops off
一个500美元的礼物
a $500 gift
你说她没有想与你复合的意思?
and she's not trying to get back together with you?
你也许说的对
Maybe you're right.
或者她只是说她所想 只是表示友好
Or she's telling the truth and just being nice.
你说的也挺对
Maybe you're right.
哇喔 我太容易被人牵着鼻子了
Wow, I am easy to manipulate.
嘿各位 是Emily
Oh, guys, it's Emily.
我该怎么办?
What should I do?
好吧 接 表现强硬一点
Okay, answer it. Just be strong.
如果她开始哭 记得不要做任何承诺
And if she starts to cry, don't make any promises.
更重要的是 开免提我们也能听到
And most importantly, put it on speaker so we can hear.
嘿?
Hello?
嘿 我是Emily
Hey, it's Emily.
现在说话方便吗?
Is this a good time?
当然 当然 好 怎么了?
Yeah, yeah. Sure. What's up?
你对那个礼物还满意吗?
Was it okay I left that gift?
我真希望我们还能成朋友
I'm really hoping we can be friends.
也许 也许吧
Maybe, maybe.
呃 你想一起出来喝杯咖啡吗?
Um, you think you'd want to grab a cup of coffee?
还在吗?
Hello?
对不起 我刚刚只是花了一点时间
I'm sorry, I seem to be taking an annoying amount of time
想想该如何决定这件事!
deciding how I feel about this!
我只是... 我想念我们在一起的日子
I just... I miss hanging out with you.
感觉不是我失去了一个朋友 是我失去了我最好的朋友
It's not like I lost a friend, it's like I lost my best friend.
还可不可能
Is there any chance
你来我这儿一次?
you'd want to come over?
对不起 我觉得这不是一个好想法
I'm sorry, I don't think that's a good idea.
好吧 我只是...
Okay. I'm just...
我只是这段时间比较难熬
I'm having a really hard time,
但是这不是你的问题 是我自己的
but that's not your problem, that's mine.
我... 我不会再打扰你了
I... I won't bother you again,
但是请你记住你永远在我的心里有一席之地
but please know that you'll always have a place in my heart.
再见 Raj
Bye, Raj.
你是个好人
You're a good guy.
再见 Emily
Good-bye, Emily.
这也太残酷了 各位
That was rough, you guys.
我知道 但是你做到了 我为你骄傲
I know, but you did it. I'm so proud of you.
哎 好吧 我就不打扰你们的女生之夜了
Well, anyway, I'll leave you to your girls' night.
你确定你不想和我们呆在这里?
Are you sure you don't want to stay here with us?
不了 我想自己静一静
No, I kind of feel like being alone right now.
好吧 如果你改变了想法 我们都在这里
Well, if you change your mind, we'll be here.
谢了
Thank you.
代我们向Emily问好
Say hi to Emily for us.
必须的
Will do.
我觉得这份合约还可以
This contract looks good to me.
我觉得非常好
I'll say it looks good.
用了我独占的字体 Shelvetica
苹果电脑默认字体Helvetica
我本来想吐槽一下的
I want to say something obnoxious,
但是这字体的确容易看
but it is easy on the eyes.
我有点累了 Howie 准备走吗?
I'm a little tired, Howie. You ready to go?
好 等等 等我签了这个合同
Yeah, one sec. I just need to sign this contract.
- 什么合同?  - 呃 我们遇到了一个问题
- What is it?  - Well, we ran into a problem
就是我专利所有权的问题 所以我们想着
about my share of the patent, so we're forming
组建一个合伙公司来平分所有权
a partnership to split anything we make equally.
Sheldon 是你起草的这份合同吗?
Sheldon, did you draft the contract?
当然是我
You bet I did.
嗯 今晚你俩一定会使劲亲热一番
Oh. You're gonna make out so hard tonight.
所以 你想直接就签了
So, you're just gonna sign this
都不事先让律师看一看?
without having a lawyer look at it?
不好意思
Excuse me.
我从幼儿园就开始起草合同了
I've been drafting contracts since kindergarten.
不需要律师教我用手指画画
Didn't need a lawyer to get me out of finger painting.
现在更不需要
Don't need one now.
- 我知道 但是...  - Bernie
- I know, but...  - Bernie,
是他们很贴心地找了一个方法
the guys were nice enough to find a way
来让我不被踢出局
to keep me from being cut out.
好吧 我希望是这样
Well, I should hope so.
整件事是你的想法
The whole thing was your idea.
呃 公平地说 Howard的想法是建立在Sheldon的数学上的
Well, to be fair, Howard's idea was based on Sheldon's math.
各位 每个人都参与进来了 好吗?
Guys, everyone is involved in this, okay?
Howard的想法
Howard's invention,
Sheldon的数学 我的初始理论
Sheldon's math, my original theory
是我提出时空像超冷液体的理论
that space-time was like a supercooled liquid.
我相信Penny也会提到这个
Which I'm sure Penny would've mentioned
如果她现在没有一直玩她的手指
if she wasn't working on that hangnail right now.
啥?
What?
亲爱的 这很好啊
Honey, this is fine.
如果你想签一个Sheldon编的合同
If you want to sign a contract that Sheldon whipped up,
那就签吧
go ahead.
我们能去走廊上说吗?
Can I talk to you in the hall?
当然 稍等一下
Sure. Excuse us.
- 嘿 Leonard  - 什么?
- Hey, Leonard.  - What?
如果她觉得我们不应该申请这项专利的话
If she doesn't think that we should apply for this patent,
那她就专的是太可笑了
she's being patently absurd.
笑点不错
Good one.
太好了 你明白了
Okay, you got it.
我还担心你要想一会儿呢
See, I was afraid it was a thinker.
- 你到底在干什么?  - 我只是想确保
What are you doing? I just want to make sure
你认真全面地考虑了这件事
you've thought this through.
还有什么可想的? 我们有了一项发明
What's to think about? We have an invention
而且还想更进一步
and want to move forward.
Howie 你现在要做的是和Sheldon Cooper
Howie, you're about to form a legal partnership
形成法律意义上的合作关系
with Sheldon Cooper.
好吧 如果你是想冷静地戳中要害的话
All right, if you're gonna calmly make excellent points,
我就不确定要不要和你说话了
then I don't know if I want to talk to you.
好了 我明白
Okay. I get it.
你这么担心我实在很贴心
And it's sweet that you're worried about me,
但我能照顾好自己
but I can take care of myself.
我不是在担心你 我是在担心我自己
I'm not worried about you. I'm worried about me.
我不想这么辛苦怀胎十月的时候还要
I don't want to go through this pregnancy listening
比现在更多地听你抱怨Sheldon
to you complain about Sheldon driving you crazy
又怎么把你逼疯了
more than you already do.
现在我们又开始死循环了
Here we go with the ironclad logic again.
你以前就已经试过和他一起工作了
You've tried to work with him before.
结果并不理想
It hasn't gone well.
这次又怎么会有什么不同?
Why is this time gonna be any different?
你是不是借用了宝宝的神力?
Is the fetus helping you?
这算作弊你造吗
'Cause that's cheating.
- 你好?  - 嘿 Raj
- Hello?  - Hey, Raj.
我是Claire 你好吗?
It's Claire. How are you?
你好 我很好 真的很好
Hi. I'm good. Really good.
额 我也不知道为什么要说 "真的狠好"
Well, I don't know why I said "really good."
我其实只是一般好
I'm just regular good.
我真的很想听上去自信一点
I really just wanted to sound confident.
这里的 "真的" 是真的 “真的”
And that "really" was a real "really,"
不像第一个 “真的” 其实是假的
not a fake "really" like the first "really."
真的?
Really?
我不知道 我迷失了 也错过了高速出口
I don't know. I lost track and I missed my exit.
那么... 你咋了?
So, uh... so what's up?
上次我们聊天的时候
Well, last time we talked,
我刚和我男朋友和好了
I had just gotten back together with my boyfriend,
但我希望你知道我们最终还是没法在一起
and I wanted to let you know that things didn't work out.
真的咩? 我很抱歉
Really? I'm sorry.
我绝对不是只会这一句
I swear I know other words.
如果你还是想的话...
So if you were still interested...
我有! 真的有! 绝对有! 非常有!
Yes! Indeed! Absolutely! Indubitably!
其实我都不知道啥叫“非常有”
I'm not even sure what the last one means,
但我好歹没有一直说“真的”了
but it's another word, and I know it.
那么
So, uh,
你想什么时候见一面呢?
when do you want to meet up?
我马上就下班了
Uh, I'm almost off work.
你现在在做什么?
What are you doing now?
现... 现在啊 这个...
R... Right now, well...
这个 其实 我也不想对你有所隐瞒
Well, actually, to... to be completely honest,
我打算去看看我的前女友
I'm stopping by to see my ex-girlfriend
因为她现在是在不太好 但是...
because she's having a tough time. But...
这并不代表我们就要和好什么的
it's not like we're getting back together or anything.
让我猜猜看 关于分手最惨的一部分莫过于
Let me guess, the worst part about breaking up
她已经不再有能说话的好朋友了?
is that she doesn't have her best friend to talk to anymore?
这和她说的一模一样
That's exactly what she said!
你是怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
我也是个女的 这就像恋爱守则第一章
I'm a girl. It's, like, page one out of the playbook.
你能不能给我也发一份PDF版那个守则呢?
Any chance you could send me a PDF of that playbook?
他们出去有一会儿了
They've been out there a while.
我希望没出什么事
I hope everything's okay.
我想知道他们在谈什么 如果你们几个
I wonder what they're talking about. If you guys
能闭嘴的话 我就知道了
would shut up, I could tell you.
噢
Oh.
淡定 淡定 淡定
Be cool, be cool, be cool.
嘿
Hey.
嗨 你俩没事吧?
Hello. Hey. You guys all right?
没事 我们一直在谈
Yeah. But, um, we were talking,
其实... 我有点担心
and... I'm a little concerned
我们三个之间的合作伙伴关系
about the three of us forming a partnership.
你是在说我们的有限责任公司吗?
Are you suggesting a limited liability corporation?
因为公子我真司没想到喔
'Cause I did not L-L-see that coming.
Sheldon 我不是担心钱的事
Sheldon, my concern is not with the money or anything.
而是你对我的态度
It's... it's with how you treat me.
我相信我对你还是很大度的
Well, I believe I'm treating you generously.
这也是为什么我在起草合同的时候
That's why I've stipulated in the contract
提及你对这项发明的贡献
that your contributions to our invention
和我自己的一样有价值
are as valuable as my own.
你的意思是他的贡献
Are you saying that his contributions
实际上没有你的有价值吗?
aren't as valuable as yours?
不 我没有那么说
No, I am not saying that,
因为我今早一直在不停地那么说
because I kept saying that this morning
然后Leonard说 "不要一直说了"
and Leonard said, "Stop saying that""
看到了吗? 这就是我们每一次合作都会发生的事
See? This is what happens every time we work together.
等等
You know what, hang on.
如果Sheldon别无选择
What if Sheldon had no choice
只能恭恭敬敬呢?
but to be respectful?
这又是什么我们不知道的隐藏开关吗?
Is there a switch on the back of his neck we don't know about?
不
No.
我指的是你们可以在合同里加上一条
What I'm saying is you could add a clause to the contract
禁止他调笑Howard的规定
that he can't make fun of Howard.
那要如何执行呢?
How would you enforce it?
拜托 我签署的任何合同
Oh, please. Any contract I sign
都是靠我自己的道德准则执行的
is enforced by my own personal code of ethics.
还有他的强迫症
And his obsessive-compulsive disorder.
对 那个也是
Yeah, that, too.
过去一点
And scoot over.
你的影子跑到我的专座上了
Part of your shadow's on my spot.
Howard 你觉得如何?
Howard, what do you think?
我同意
I'm on board.
我立刻就加上
I'll add it right now.
哦耶 现在是附件时间!
Oh, baby, it's addendum time!
喂?
Hello?
嘿 Emily 听着
Hey, Emily, listen,
我想了一下 我觉得
I've been thinking, and I'm not sure
我过去不太合适
it's a good idea that I come over.
哦
Oh.
好 我理解
Okay. I understand.
别啊 你别哭啊
No, no. Please don't cry.
好 那我不哭!
Okay, I'll stop!
喂?
Hello?
嘿 Claire 计划有变...
Hey, so, listen, Claire, change of plans...
好 你爱咋办咋办吧 但是她在耍你呢
Fine. Do what you want, but she's playing you.
我不这么认为 听起来她很难过
I don't think so. She sounded pretty upset.
你指的是...
You mean like...
"我真的很想见你
"I was just really looking forward to seeing you.
我一整天都过得很糟"这种吗
I'm having such a rough day."
Emily 你听着...
Emily, listen...
很抱歉
I'm sorry,
但我不能去
but I can't come by.
为什么不能?
Why not?
我想我们都很清楚如果我过去的话
I think we both know if I come over,
- 我们又会复合...  - 我跟你说了
- we're gonna get back together and...  - I told you
我需要一个朋友
I needed a friend.
不然你以为呢?
What do you think is happening here?
我待会儿打给你
Call you right back.
我做的修改从第四页开始
The-the revisions I made start on page four.
哇 有好多"于是"啊
Wow. That is a lot of "whereupons".
那你该看看他给我的情人节卡片
You should see the Valentine's Day card he gave me.
"第三条 基于此项目
"Article three: As it pertains to this project,
"Sheldon博士承诺戒除对于Howard Wolowitz
"Dr. Sheldon Cooper promises to abstain from all insulting or
"的一切侮辱和不敬言论
"disrespectful language directed toward Howard Wolowitz,
"包括但不限于对于工程学的嘲笑
"including but not limited to: mockery of engineering,
"他的身高 头发 衣橱
"his height, his hair, his wardrobe,
"以及他对于电影幽灵骑士的
"and his insane belief that the Ghost Rider movie
"没那么糟"的评价
was, quote, 'not that bad.'"
等等 或许应该加上
Hang on. Maybe there should be a "no insult" clause
关于我的"禁止侮辱"条款
about me, too.
- 你还喜欢香菜吗?  - 是啊
- Do you still like cilantro?  - Yeah.
那我做不到啊
You're tying my hands here.
- 好吧 那我们签字吧  - 等等
- All right, let's sign this.  - Wait, wait, wait.
第六页做了什么改动?
What are these changes on page six?
Sheldon 你改了什么?
Sheldon, what did you do?
我该知道的
I should've known.
"Sheldon Cooper25%的收益
"25% of profits
将被分配用于Howard 和 Bernadette Wolowitz夫妇
"due to Sheldon Cooper will be allocated to a scholarship fund
第一个孩子的奖学金基金"
for the firstborn child of Howard and Bernadette Wolowitz""
Sheldon 这真是太好了
Sheldon, that's so nice.
这一条打败了
That beats
我想在Gap给他们买的
the onesie I was gonna get them
婴儿连体衣
from babyGap.
Sheldon 这样真是太大方了
That's very generous, Sheldon.
我一直觉得教育比金钱重要
Oh, I've always valued education over money.
你需要书面文件以保证尊重
And the very fact that you needed a written guarantee
让我意识到
of respect made me realize
我对你的贡献多么轻视
how dismissive I've been of your contributions.
我只是希望
I appreciate that. And I just hope
这个奖学金可以让你们的小孩
that this scholarship can rescue your child
免受低水平的教育
from the subpar education
不要过工程师的枯燥生活
and menial life of an engineer.
- Sheldon  - 咋啦
- Sheldon.  - What?
这不是还没签字嘛
I didn't sign it yet.
我明白你的意思
I hear what you're saying,
但是我认识Emily很久了
but I've known Emily a long time,
我觉得她跟别人不一样
and I think she deserves the benefit of the doubt.
好吧 这是你自己的事
All right, it's your life.
但是你知道结局会如何
But you know how this is gonna end.
事实上 我很清楚
As a matter of fact, I do.
我会去安慰她一下 因为我是一个在朋
I'm gonna comfort her, because I'm a caring
友需要倾诉的时候乐于倾听
and decent friend who's happy to be there
而且作风正派的人
when she needs someone to talk to.
真是愉快的谈话
Good talk.